sroutraykec@gmail.com

Skills

Excellent technical knowledge of Java for Android, Dart for Flutter and Android Studio.

Experience with Firebase Authentication, Crash Reporting, Push Notifications, Realtime Database, Firebase Storage and Cloud Firestore.

Solid understanding of mobile development life cycle, MVP, MVVM, BLoC pattern.

Knowledge of Android and iOS UI design principles, patterns and material design.

Thorough knowledge of Activities, Services, Intents, Widgets.

Ability to translate the designs and wireframes into high quality responsive UI code.

Good working knowledge of SQLite database.

Familiarity with RESTful APIs and libraries.

Basic understanding of Git.

Experience

Dec 2019 - PRESENT

Freelance Flutter developer

- Developed a local grocery delivery app and have implemented payment gateway.
- Created an ecommerce app for a lifestyle fashion brand.
- Designed and implemented a newspaper app which fetches latest news. It allows users to save articles to read later and also has options to block the news they do not want to see.

Technology: Android studio, Dart, Firebase, REST APIs, SQLite, Google Maps integration

June 2017 - Nov 2019

Freelance Android developer

- Developed a high quality, sustainable healthcare app that removes the need of paper based prescription writing and scanning the prescription for record keeping.
- Designed and built an app for a premium institute for civil services to provide study material and recorded video lectures to their students.
- Implemented an app for learning Odia language with multiple tabs.

Technology: Android studio, APIs, Core Java, SQLite

Freelance *Manual tester*

- Used various methods to test the user interface of the application.
- Continuously updated testing documentation.
- Involved in maintaining and executing the Test Cases.
- Understanding test requirements and deriving test scenarios.
- Raised tickets to report bugs and other issues and worked closely with other team members to get those fixed.

June 2015 - March 2016

Pylabs - Web Developer

- Gathered business rules and requirements for a large US insurance company at its early stages.
- Maintenance and further development of new features.
- Worked as a development team member, and gradually became responsible for many areas of the software development (rates, endorsements, claims, document management, complex web forms).

Technology: Python, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

2

Aug 2014 - May 2015

MedRC Edutech Pvt ltd - Content Development Executive

- Built website with WordPress.
- Modifying existing code as needed.
- Assistance in website performance monitoring and SEO.

Education

2007 - 2011

B. Tech in Applied Electronics & Instrumentation

Krupajal Engineering College (BPUT), Odisha